const dataRCC = [
    {
        question: "According to I.S. : 456, slabs which span in two directions with corners held down, are assumed to be divided in each direction into middle strips and edge strips such that the width of the middle strip, is",
        optionA: "Half of the width of the slab",
        optionB: "Two-third of the width of the slab",
        optionC: "Three-fourth of the width of the slab",
        optionD: "Four-fifth of the width of the slab",
        correct: "c"
    },
    {
        question: "The bond stress at a section can be reduced by",
        optionA: "Decreasing the lever arm",
        optionB: "Increasing the total perimeter of bars",
        optionC: "Replacing larger bars by greater number of small bars",
        optionD: "Replacing smaller bars by greater number of greater bars",
        correct: "c"
    },
    {
        question: "The width of column strip in a flat slab as per IS 456 is kept",
        optionA: "0.25 times the span length",
        optionB: "0.25 times the diameter of the column",
        optionC: "0.5 times the span length",
        optionD: "0.5 times the diameter of the column",
        correct: "a"
    },
    {
        question: "If 'W' is the uniformly distributed load on a circular slab of radius 'R' fixed at its ends, the maximum positive radial or circumferential moment at its center, is",
        optionA: "3WR²/16",
        optionB: "2WR²/16",
        optionC: "WR²/16",
        optionD: "None of above",
        correct: "c"
    },
    {
        question: "If 'W' is the uniformly distributed load on a circular slab of radius 'R' fixed at its ends, the maximum negative radial moment at its end, is",
        optionA: "-3WR²/16",
        optionB: "-2WR²/16",
        optionC: "-WR²/16",
        optionD: "None of above",
        correct: "b"
    },
    {
        question: "If 'W' is the uniformly distributed load on a circular slab of radius 'R' fixed at its ends, the maximum circumferential moment at its end, is",
        optionA: "-3WR²/16",
        optionB: "-2WR²/16",
        optionC: "-WR²/16",
        optionD: "0",
        correct: "d"
    },
    {
        question: "If 'W' is the uniformly distributed load on a circular slab of radius 'R' simply supported at its ends, the maximum positive radial or circumferential moment at its center, is",
        optionA: "3WR²/16",
        optionB: "2WR²/16",
        optionC: "WR²/16",
        optionD: "None of above",
        correct: "a"
    },
    {
        question: "If 'W' is the uniformly distributed load on a circular slab of radius 'R' simply supported at its ends, the maximum circumferential moment at its end, is",
        optionA: "3WR²/16",
        optionB: "2WR²/16",
        optionC: "WR²/16",
        optionD: "None of above",
        correct: "b"
    },
    {
        question: "If 'W' is the uniformly distributed load on a circular slab of radius 'R' simply supported at its ends, the maximum radial moment at its end, is",
        optionA: "3WR²/16",
        optionB: "2WR²/16",
        optionC: "WR²/16",
        optionD: "0",
        correct: "d"
    },
    {
        question: "The maximum ratio of span to depth of a slab simply supported and spanning in one direction is",
        optionA: "35",
        optionB: "25",
        optionC: "30",
        optionD: "20",
        correct: "c"
    },
    {
        question: "The maximum ratio of span to depth of a continous slab and spanning in one direction is",
        optionA: "35",
        optionB: "25",
        optionC: "30",
        optionD: "20",
        correct: "a"
    },
    {
        question: "The maximum ratio of span to depth of a slab simply supported (spanning in two direction) is",
        optionA: "25",
        optionB: "30",
        optionC: "35",
        optionD: "40",
        correct: "c"
    },
    {
        question: "The maximum ratio of span to depth of a continous slab (spanning in two direction) is",
        optionA: "25",
        optionB: "30",
        optionC: "35",
        optionD: "40",
        correct: "d"
    },
    {
        question: "If the width of the foundation for two equal columns is restricted, the shape of the footing generally adopted is",
        optionA: "Square",
        optionB: "Rectangular",
        optionC: "Trapezoidal",
        optionD: "Triangular",
        correct: "b"
    },
    {
        question: "The floor slab of a building is supported on reinforced cement floor beams. The ratio of the end and intermediate spans is 'generally' kept",
        optionA: "0.7",
        optionB: "0.8",
        optionC: "0.9",
        optionD: "0.6",
        correct: "c"
    },
    {
        question: "Pick up the correct statement from the following:",
        optionA: "Lateral reinforcement in R.C.C. columns is provided to prevent the longitudinal reinforcement from buckling",
        optionB: "Lateral reinforcement prevents the shearing of concrete on diagonal plane",
        optionC: "Lateral reinforcement stops breaking away of concrete cover, due to buckling",
        optionD: "All of the above",
        correct: "d"
    },
    {
        question: "Lapped splices in tensile reinforcement are generally not used for bars of size larger than",
        optionA: "20 mm φ",
        optionB: "25 mm φ",
        optionC: "32 mm φ",
        optionD: "36 mm φ",
        correct: "d"
    },
    {
        question: "Minimum spacing between horizontal parallel reinforcement of the same size should not be less than",
        optionA: "One diameter",
        optionB: "1.5 diameter",
        optionC: "2 diameter",
        optionD: "2.5 diameter",
        correct: "a"
    },
    {
        question: "Columns may be made of plain concrete if their unsupported lengths do not exceed their least lateral dimension",
        optionA: "Two times",
        optionB: "Three times",
        optionC: "Four times",
        optionD: "Five times",
        correct: "b"
    },
    {
        question: "A pre-stressed concrete member is preferred because",
        optionA: "Its dimensions are not decided from the diagonal tensile stress",
        optionB: "Large size of long beams carrying large shear force need not be adopted",
        optionC: "Removal of cracks in the members due to shrinkage",
        optionD: "All the above",
        correct: "d"
    },
    {
        question: "A pile of length 'L' carrying a uniformly distributed load 'W' per metre length is suspended at center, the maximum B.M. at the centre of the pile is",
        optionA: "WL²/8 ",
        optionB: "WL²/24 ",
        optionC: "WL²/47 ",
        optionD: "WL²/90 ",
        correct: "a"
    },
    {
        question: "A pile of length 'L' carrying a uniformly distributed load 'W' per metre length is suspended at two points, the maximum B.M. at the centre of the pile or at the points of suspension is",
        optionA: "WL²/8 ",
        optionB: "WL²/24 ",
        optionC: "WL²/47 ",
        optionD: "WL²/90 ",
        correct: "c"
    },
    {
        question: "A pile of length 'L' carrying a uniformly distributed load 'W' per metre length is suspended at three points, the maximum B.M. at the centre of the pile is",
        optionA: "WL²/8 ",
        optionB: "WL²/24 ",
        optionC: "WL²/47 ",
        optionD: "WL²/90 ",
        correct: "d"
    },
    {
        question: "The maximum permissible size of aggregates suitable for the construction of cement concrete floor is",
        optionA: "7.5 mm",
        optionB: "10 mm",
        optionC: "12.5 mm",
        optionD: "15 mm",
        correct: "b"
    },
    {
        question: "The minimum thickness of the cover at the end of a reinforcing bar should not be less than twice the diameter of the bar subject to a minimum of",
        optionA: "10 mm",
        optionB: "15 mm",
        optionC: "20 mm",
        optionD: "25 mm",
        correct: "d"
    },
    /* {
        question: "",
        optionA: "",
        optionB: "",
        optionC: "",
        optionD: "",
        correct: ""
    }, */



]
//module.exports = dataRCC

const Random = (data) => {
    const num = 5;
    const res = [];
    for (let i = 0; i < num;) {
        const random = Math.floor(Math.random() * data.length);
        if (res.indexOf(data[random]) !== -1) {
            continue;
        };
        res.push(data[random]);
        i++;
    };
    return res;
};
const rccRandom = Random(dataRCC)

export { dataRCC, rccRandom }
//module.exports = rccRandom